Daehwa Kim

291, Daehak-ro, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon, Republic of Korea daehwakim@kaist.ac.kr • +82 6860 8558 • https://daehwa.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research goal is engineering for a fluid interface, exploring a seamless integration of a computer and human that makes new and pleasant experiences. My prior research lies in (a) sensing and interaction techniques for a mobile device and (b) novel sensing technologies supporting sophisticated hand inputs. I published full papers at ACM CHI and UIST.

Sensing Techniques for Fluid Interfaces	novel sensing technologies supporting sophisticated hand inputs	sensing and interaction techniques for a mobile device
	AtaTouch (Cond. Accepted CHl'21) + MagTouch (CHl'20)	OddEyeCam (UIST'20)OmniSense (Ongoing)

EDUCATION

KAIST, School of Computing

Mar 2019 – Feb 2021 (Expected)

- M.S. student at Human-Computer Interaction Lab
 - Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" (To be)
 - Adviser: Prof. Geehyuk Lee
 - Focus: Sensing Techniques

UNIST, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Mar 2015 – Feb 2019

- B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering (Major)
- B.S. in Electrical Engineering (Minor)
 - Thesis: "VRone: 3D Force Feedback System in VR Using a Commercial Drone"
 - Entered with top honors.
- Summer session program, ual: (University of the Arts London), London, UK

Jul 2018

PUBLICATIONS

CONFERENCES

- [1] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return-Loss" in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan. (full paper, Conditionally Accepted)
- [2] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "OddEyeCam: A Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" in *Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*, Virtual Event, USA, Oct 2020. (full paper)
- [3] Keunwoo Park, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Seongkook Heo, and Geehyuk Lee, "MagTouch: Robust Finger Identification for a Smartwatch Using a Magnet Ring and a Built-in Magnetometer" in *Proceedings* of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA, Apr 2020. (full paper)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

HCI Lab, KAIST

Undergraduate Research Student, School of Computing

Mar 2018 – Jun 2018

Jan 2018 - Mar 2018

- Project: PCB design for a hand gesture sensing wristband.
- · Supervisors: Prof. Geehyuk Lee
- · Focus: human-computer interaction, PCB design, physical prototyping

Hyper-connected Communication Research Laboratory, ETRI

- Research Intern, IoT Research Division
 - Project: Smart Home project Building IoT lighting system controlled by user's voice
 - Supervisors: Dr Jungsik Sung and Daeho Kim
 - · Focus: IoT network system, Natural language processing

iHCI Lab (Intelligent Human Computer Interaction Lab), UNIST

Undergraduate Research Student, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Feb 2017 – Nov 2017

- Project: Finger Joystick Interaction
- Supervisors: Prof. Sungahn Ko
- Focus: human-computer interaction, visualization

AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS	 4th Prize, NAVER x UNIST Undergraduate Poster Award Topic: "VibCat: Vibration Categorization for Input and Interaction". Awarded by NAVER CEO. 	Dec 2017	
	Received an award of 1,000,000 KRW.		
	Excellence Award, World Friends ICT volunteers return report 2016	Dec 2016	
	 Dispatched to Uzbekistan to provide Android development lectures to university students. Awarded by the Director of National Information Society Agency. 		
	 Received an award of Samsung Galaxy Tab 4 10.1. 		
	Academic Achievement Award, UNIST		
	 2017 Fall Academic Achievement Award: GPA 4.05/4.3 	Jan 2018	
	2017 Spring Academic Achievement Award: GPA 3.98/4.3	Jul 2017	
	 2016 Fall Academic Achievement Award: GPA 3.90/4.3 	Feb 2016	
	2016 Spring Academic Achievement Award: GPA 4.06/4.3	Aug 2016	
	 2015 Spring Academic Achievement Award: GPA 4.00/4.3 	Jul 2015	
	Uni-Star Scholarship, UNIST	Mar 2015 – Feb 2019	
	Entered with top honors.		
	 Tuition + academic support fee of 1,000,000 KRW were paid each semester. Overseas Training Scholarship, UNIST 	Jun 2018	
	• Financial aid for the summer session program at University of the Arts London		
TEACHING	Teaching Assistant, AI Lab - Learning Commons II, UNIST	Sep 2018 – Dec 2018	
EXPERIENCE	Head of Android Developement Team, HeXA, UNIST	Feb 2017 – Dec 2017	
	Instructor, Tashkent University of Information Technologies (TUIT)Excellence Award, World Friends ICT volunteers return report 2016	Jul 2016 – Sep 2016	
CAMPUS	D2 factory, NAVER		
ACTIVITIES	■ Campus Partner	Feb 2016 – Feb 2017	
	Hosted the 2nd Hackathon at UNIST, sponsored by NAVER and UNIST ECE		
	HeXA (Hacker's eXciting Academy), UNIST		
	 A computer security & development research group 		
	■ Vice-President	Feb 2016 – Feb 2017	
	 Head of Android development team 	Feb 2017 – Dec 2017	
	Provided regular anndroid-development lectures for club members		
	UNIST Media Center, UNIST		
	■ Video Editor	Mar 2015 – Feb 2017	
	Representative work		
	 My Age 22 - Travel to Europe with a drone Web drama: The town where engineers live 		
PROJECTS	Audio Hero	Sep 2019 – Dec 2019	
	 Sound-based danger detection system using VGGish deep learning model 	3cp 2013	
	 Skills: Deep learning, Signal processing 		
	VRone	Sep 2018 – Dec 2018	
	 3-dimensional force feedback in VR using a personal and commercial drone Skills: Unity C# programming, Android programming 	r	
	System Light 2.0 @ ETRI	Jan 2018 – Mar 2018	
	 Smart Home project - Building IoT system for lights 		
	Skills: Computer network, Natural language processing		
	VibCat	Oct 2017 – Dec 2017	
	 Vibration Categorization for Input & Interaction 		
	 Skills: Machine learning, Android programming 		
	Finger joystick interaction	Feb 2017 – Nov 2017	
	 Interaction technique to support finger's directional input using capacitive image of a smartwatch's touchscreen 		
	Skills: Machine learning, Android programming	N. 2045 Y 2015	
	Doom a moment	Mar 2017 - Jun 2017	

Poem a moment

Mar 2017 – Jun 2017

- An android application that shows Yoon Dongju's poems on the wallpaper
- Available on Google Play store (download 1000+)
- Skills: Android programming

TUIT Android Lecture

Jun 2016 - Sep 2016

- Android development lecture provided to TUIT university students
- Skills: Android programming, Object-oriented programming

Mr.Bill

Jun 2016 – Jul 2016

- Algorithm and system to provide optimal Dutch pay way
- Available on Google Play store (download 500+)
- Skills: Android programming, Graph theory

[CV compiled on 2020-12-14 for Acme Corporation]